Read this poem.
I could tell at a glance it was yours.
Please forgive me.
I didn’t know my place.
What do you think? Am I amazing?
Who are you?
You’re not my younger brother.
Ah!
My lord!
I told you I'm a doctor.
The Fool represents a new beginning.
You’re about to start a new role and new relationships
somewhere far, far away.
Am I going to fall in love with a foreigner?
That’s not what the card says.
It says they’re from your country.
You can hesitate, but don’t lie to yourself.
Deep down, you know how you feel,
but something make you afraid
or uncertain.
I wish I could bathe with you like this
every day.
You can.
I’m sorry.
It’s alright.
We didn’t know each other.
What happened back then
wasn’t anyone’s fault.
But this time,
we both know
that our duty is to remain loyal
and faithful to the king.
Isn’t that right?
Yes.
Can’t sleep again?
You too?
Then come drink with me.
The moon is beautiful.
That’s why I wish it could stay forever.
If the moonlight were to disappear,
how heartbroken would those who admire it be?
When the moon sets,
the sun rises.
Its brilliant light
outshines the moon.
The sun blazes with scorching heat.
Anyone who gets too close may get burned.
Unlike the moon, whose light is gentle.
If my wish could come true,
I’d hold on to the moon and never let it go.
Then,
if someone longs for something
they can never have,
should they keep hoping?
Desire comes from the heart.
You can’t force a heart to stop longing.
Unless you know for certain that it’s impossible.
The sooner you let go,
the less it’ll hurt.
I’m going back to my room.
Gaew.
Yes?
Come sit with me.
Just now,
what were you talking about?
Just random things
like love.
Is P’Sri in love?
That’s right.
With who?
I don’t know.
Do you...
have someone in your heart?
I’m asking you.
Do you like someone?
Why do you want to know?
I asked first,
so you should answer first.
I guess I do.
I answered your question.
Now it’s your turn.
Why do you want to know?
Love is such a curious thing.
Even when you shouldn’t,
it’s so hard to stop yourself.
That doesn’t answer my question.
You’ve fallen for someone, haven’t you?
At first,
I wasn’t sure.
But now,
I’m certain.
Is it someone I’ve met before?
What do they look like?
Can you tell me?
Do you really want to know?
Yes.
Then…
go look into a looking glass,
and you shall find the answer.
A looking glass?
What’s that?
A mirror?
P'Muen.
I’m done, my lord.
Nothing in this world compares to loving you.
I can’t stay by your side,
despite loving you with all my heart,
You’re not me.
You’ll never know how deeply this hurts.
To love someone, but can’t be with them.
A love that burns your heart to ashes.
Is that right?
Yes, my lord.
Your turn.
Understood.
O moon, my heart’s true desire.
Your radiant light is forever engraved in my heart.
Your gentle voice has captured my soul.
Yet you remain beyond my reach.
O, how I long to call you mine.
What’s gotten into you two?
One’s heart is burning with love,
while the other’s hiding it deeply.
Maybe Lord Sriprach
has fallen for someone who’s already taken.
That's what i think.
Your turn,
Consort Thao-Srichulaluck.
To love you,
my heart yearns to see you.
When we’re apart, my heart feels restless
Perhaps this is love,
yet fate and duty
leave me no choice.
Better hide it than be destroyed.
What does your poem mean?
Duty comes before everything else.
So,
your poem means
that you can’t control love,
but duty outweighs everything,
so you can’t follow your feelings.
Am I right?
Three poems. Three hearts.
Yet somehow, they seem like one story.
Listen.
Love isn’t wrong.
But if you choose to love,
choose carefully.
So you won’t have to hide it
or let it burn you alive.
Wad.
What are you doing here, Reung?
I wanted to try cockfighting,
so I came.
Are you sure?
Of course.
Why?
Do you really not know?
The one you brought is a hen.
Oh.
I just–
Spare me the excuse.
Everyone knows you hate loud noises.
No one’s buying your excuse.
Just tell the truth.
Why are you really here?
Well, I…
Wad.
Whether you meant to or not,
I want you to think it over.
We’re friends anyway.
Do what you have to do.
Dech, you’re better now?
Yeah, I’m all good.
-How did you—
-Dech.
Come check out my new chicken.
Sure.
Gaew.
I’m sorry
for messing with you that day,
and causing Dech trouble.
I’ve forgotten all about it.
I should apologize too.
I lost my temper that day.
Thank you.
Gaew.
You invited me here,
so why do you keep talking to Wad?
Come here.
Yes.
Let’s get started.
Go, Thongkam!
Night Fury, don’t lose.
Okay?
Do you want to use my hen?
No, save it for laying eggs.
Go!
Come on!
That’s it, Thongkam!
Good job!
Your rooster’s good.
Thanks, Reung.
Well done, Wad.
Today is a good day.
All my friends are together.
I’m really happy.
Drink up.
Cheers.
It’s been a long time since we drank together.
Guys,
want to play a game?
What’s a game?
A game is a pastime.
This one’s called
“Yes or No.”
I’ll spin P’Dech’s dagger.
Whoever it points to
has to answer a question with…
“Yes.” or “No.”
If it’s yes, you say, “Yes, of course.”
If it’s no, or you don’t want to answer,
you lose.
Then you have to take a shot.
Let’s play.
P’Muen.
Me?
Here’s your question.
Do you like sneaking glances at me?
Dech.
Yes, of course.
Hm?
But I only keep an eye on you
because I’m worried you’ll go fooling around.
That’s all.
You’re acting all cool.
Reung.
Come on.
Round two.
P’Muen again.
Me again?
The question is…
Do you enjoy being alone with me?
Yes or no?
Uh…
Yes, of course.
I always see him smiling from ear to ear
whenever he’s alone with you.
Pin, shut up!
Sorry, my lord.
You little…
Damn.
Alright.
Round three.
Oh!
P'Muen!
Huh?
Why does it keep pointing at me?
Are you messing with me?
I’m not.
Alright.
I’ll ask the last question.
If I disappeared from here,
would you miss me?
Yes or no?
I'll miss you.
Is that so, Dech?
If any of my friends here
were to disappear,
I’d miss every one of them.
Is that so?
That’s right.
Wad.
Do you want to play this game with Reung?
-No.
-I do.
I want to play with Yam.
Who wants to play with you?
Come on, Yam.
It’s just for fun.
Then
you don’t have to spin the dagger,
just take turns asking.
Then I’ll go first.
Yam.
Do you like peeping at me while I bathe? Yes or no?
Yes, of course.
Huh?
I knew it!
I only keep an eye on you to make sure
you don’t go fooling around.
If I disappeared one day,
would anyone miss me?
I don’t get it.
You lost. Drink.
Have a drink with me.
-Drink it yourself.
Come on.
Let's drink together.
Yeah?
Cheers.
Go for it!
That’s it.
Yeah,
don’t back down.
That’s the spirit.
Yam.
Do you like peeping at me while I bathe? Yes or no?
Yes, of course.
I knew it!
What am I staring at?
Stop thinking. Stop looking.
Stop.
Just stop.
Come on, you can do it.
You’re almost there.
That’s it!
Go.
You can do it.
Restrain the heart.
Don’t let your heart waver.
Don't let your mind wander afar.
Restrain the heart.
Don’t let your heart waver.
Don't let your mind wander afar.
Ah!
It's nothing.
Just a little more!
Restrain the heart.
Don’t let your heart waver.
Don't let your mind wander afar.
Restrain the heart.
Don’t let your heart waver.
Don't let your mind wander afar.
Restrain the heart.
Don’t let your heart waver.
Don't let your mind wander afar.
Ah!
What are you doing?
Nothing.
But I saw you chanting something.
What chant was that?
It’s a heart restraining spell
Restrain the heart.
Don’t let your heart waver.
Don't let your mind wander afar.
What do you use it for?
To stop myself from loving someone.
Who are you in love with?
Uh…
No one.
Restrain the heart.
Don’t let your heart waver.
Don't let your mind wander afar.
P’Muen.
-Uh…
-P’Muen.
Hold on, P’Muen.
Restrain the heart.
Don’t let your heart waver.
Don't let your mind wander afar.
What are you chanting?
I’m not chanting anything.
Are you sure?
What kind of spell is it?
Don’t come any closer.
It’s just a mosquito repelling spell.
Huh?
Mosquito Repellent?
Restrain the heart.
Don’t let your heart waver.
Don't let your mind wander afar.
Don't let your mind wander afar?
But my heart has already wandered far, P’Muen.
Restrain the heart.
Don’t let your heart waver.
Don't let your mind wander afar.
Restrain the heart.
Don’t let your heart waver.
Don't let your mind wander afar.
What are you staring at?
What’s wrong with you?
Nothing.
You’re so dead tonight.
You think I’m scared?
I can’t hold it in anymore.
Hold what?
What the hell, Pin?
I can’t hold it in anymore.
I’m leaving.
What an ass!
Where are you going?
Yam.
Can you sleep with me tonight?
Why do you want me to sleep with you?
I just asked.
So why did you come?
I can’t hold it in anymore either.
P’Muen!
P’Muen.
Where are you going?
I saw Pin packing your things this morning.
I have business in Lavo.
Lavo?
Lopburi Province?
Mhm.
Can I come with you?
I want to see Lavo with my own eyes,
and go sightseeing.
No.
I’m going to work, not to travel.
Just finish your work first,
then take me sightseeing after that.
Does Lavo have any waterfalls?
Yeah.
Then I’m coming too.
I promise I’ll be good.
Deal. Then I’ll go change first.
Gaew.
Gaew!
What does “deal” mean?
Gaew?
Gaew!
What are you doing? You scared me to death.
Were you afraid I’d drown?
Don’t ever do that again.
I just wanted to see
if I fell into the water again,
would you save me?
You know I can’t swim.
Come on, I’ll teach you.
Don’t be scared. The water’s shallow.
Hey, Gaew!
P’Muen.
Huh?
Can I ask you something?
Sure.
You like me, don’t you?
What kind of question is that?
Yes or no?
I’m being honest with you.
Can you be honest with me too?
Don’t make me keep guessing.
So…
You like me, don’t you?
Oh, my heart has belonged to none
No one ever walked in, not a single one
I believe the time will come someday
That fate will lead you to my way
Guided by fate, our paths finally crossed
Just one glance, and my heart starts to sway
Don't know why I’m carried far away
Are you the one I’ve waited for so long?
Never has my heart yearned quite this strong
If heaven decreed that we are meant to be
How could I deny the feelings inside of me?
Oh, my beloved
P'Yam.
P'Yam?
I loved you before he stole you away.
Fate has cruelly played with my heart.
I am heartbroken and cannot pretend to be happy.
I will never surrender.
I will fight until my last breath.
Gaew.
Did you leave this poem here?
This is so risky.
Give it back.
Your feelings are too obvious.
It’s dangerous, P’Sri.
What are you talking about?
Can I read your fortune?
I know a thing or two about fortune telling.
Your fate is written all over your face.
I think I can read it.
Since when did you know fortune telling?
P’Sri.
You‘re destined
to rise in rank.
Politics won’t be your downfall,
but love will.
My heart will be my downfall?
I’m not joking.
With a fate like yours,
if you keep going down this path,
your heart will bring you disaster.
At first, it’ll be a secret.
Then, an accusation.
And in the end,
it’ll become a crime.
I can see a parting.
A goodbye…
that can’t be spoken.
Believe me, P'Sri.
If you step back now,
you might be able to save your life and honor.
The way you talk…
doesn’t sound like an ordinary fortune teller.
I’m only telling you what I see.
If you don’t believe me,
it’s up to you.
You didn’t just tell me what would happen.
You even told me how it would unfold.
From a secret,
to an accusation,
to a crime.
This isn’t a guess. You already know.
Some things…
once you’ve seen them happen,
you already know how they’ll end.
You’ve seen it before?
What do you mean?
Where did you see it?
Why do you know my fate,
as if you’ve already lived through it?
Why do you know how it’ll turn out?
And why are you telling me to turn back,
as if you’ve already seen me fall?
I just don’t want you to get hurt, P’Sri.
Don't avoid my question.
Who exactly are you?
I’m…
Gaew.
Your younger brother.
No.
Gaew doesn’t know other people’s fate.
And he wouldn’t talk about parting as if he’s lived through it.
If you’re bold enough to talk about my life,
then you should be able to tell me.
Where did you come from?
Answer me.
Are you really Gaew?
Or someone else?
Who are you, really?
Are you feeling unwell?
Will this really make me feel better, P’Muen?
Trust me.
Reung.
Do you like me?
If I get to stay here,
I’ll celebrate Loy Krathong with you every year.
Confirm.
How could you do this?
You should never tell our family’s business to outsiders!
P’Khun.